<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>FAQ on Andrew Zieffler</title>
    <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/tags/faq/</link>
    <description>Recent content in FAQ on Andrew Zieffler</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.datadreaming.org/tags/faq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Q&amp;A with Becoming a Teacher of Statistics Class: Part IV</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2018-04-09-epsy-5271-part-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2018-04-09-epsy-5271-part-04/</guid>
      <description>This post is the fourth (and last) in a series of blogposts in which I respond to questions from the students in the Becoming a Teacher of Statistics course. In today’s posting I respond to questions that asked me for predictions about the future of statistics teaching and statistics education research.
Before I get into the Q&amp;amp;A, let me just state: Prediction is hard. Leland Wilkinson in The Future of Statistical Computing reminded us of this when he cited a prediction about computers that Andrew Hamilton made in a 1949 issue of Popular Mechanics</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q&amp;A with Becoming a Teacher of Statistics Class: Part III</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2018-04-02-epsy-5271-part-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2018-04-02-epsy-5271-part-03/</guid>
      <description>This post is the third in a series of blogposts in which I respond to questions from the students in the Becoming a Teacher of Statistics course. In today’s posting I respond to questions related to teaching.
With a flipped classroom, the professor tapes their lecture and has students view the video online. I think the logical extreme of this is that at some point, certain lectures will become immensely popular or polished to the point of surpassing local professors’ lectures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q&amp;A with Becoming a Teacher of Statistics Class: Part II</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2018-03-30-epsy-5271-part-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2018-03-30-epsy-5271-part-02/</guid>
      <description>This post is the second in a series of blogposts in which I respond to questions from the students in the Becoming a Teacher of Statistics course. In today’s posting I respond to questions related to several of the projects I have worked on over the years.
Can you tell us a little about your AIMS project? I think it’s not always easy for everyone to apply guidelines in order to change their behavior (in any context), but your AIMS project seems to fill that gap for stats educators-that is, it explicitly creates educational materials aligned with GAISE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q&amp;A with Becoming a Teacher of Statistics Class</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2018-03-28-epsy-5271/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2018-03-28-epsy-5271/</guid>
      <description>This last Tuesday (03/27/2018) I was invited to go do a Q&amp;amp;A with the students in the EPsy 5271 Becoming a Teacher of Statistics course. This class also met via video-link with a similar course at Penn State. The students asked thoughful (sometimes difficult) questions and I tried to answer them. I asked them if I could blog out their questions and my responses and they kindy said “yes”. Rather than respond to all of them at once, I thought I would use this opportunity to create several blogposts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
