<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>History on Andrew Zieffler</title>
    <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/tags/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in History on Andrew Zieffler</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.datadreaming.org/tags/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Computing in the &#39;60s</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2019-04-30-computer-brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2019-04-30-computer-brain/</guid>
      <description>My dad was a mathematics teacher at Sartell High School and was also really into computing and programming. I remember learning BASIC with him on our Apple IIe and also programming our TI-99/4A. (To save a program on the TI, we had to hook up an external tape recorder and write to a cassette tape. Then to run the program, you played the tape!)
 Old issues of Byte, Compute, Family Computing (check out the 1982 TV ad below), and other magazines and educational trades were stacked a mile-high in our living room; many providing the outlines of a program to create some graphical spectacle (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deprecating Statistical Significance: Toward Better Science</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2019-04-26-slhs-prosem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2019-04-26-slhs-prosem/</guid>
      <description>On Friday April 26, 2019 I gave an invited talk to the Department of Speech-Language-Hearing Sciences in their Pro-Sem series. These are really neat as they are organized by the graduate students. This is the third one of these I have given over the years and each is a treat.
In this talk I spoke about the ASA’s recent call for the deprecation of “statistical significance” and all its related variants (e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
