<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Andrew Zieffler</title>
    <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Andrew Zieffler</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.datadreaming.org/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Packages and Resources for Data Viz</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2020-12-16-packages-and-resources-for-data-viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2020-12-16-packages-and-resources-for-data-viz/</guid>
      <description>I have written several notes to myself over the years as reminders. These include ideas for research, R packages I have seen and may use sometime), things to-do, etc. I am in the process of making some of these notes more public on my blog. This will act as a more searchable, curated “note” for myself, but also makes it available to anyone else who would benefit.
These are resources I was compiling for use in our course, EPsy 1261: Understanding Data Stories through Visualization &amp;amp; Computing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some R Packages to Keep In Mind</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2020-12-15-some-r-packages-to-keep-in-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2020-12-15-some-r-packages-to-keep-in-mind/</guid>
      <description>I have written several notes to myself over the years as reminders. These include ideas for research, R packages I have seen and may use sometime), things to-do, etc. I am in the process of making some of these notes more public on my blog. This will act as a more searchable, curated “note” for myself, but also makes it available to anyone else who would benefit.
R Packages for Productivity  blastula is a package for creating beautiful custom emails in R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A History of R</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/a-history-of-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/a-history-of-r/</guid>
      <description>Tomorrow (July 23, 2020 ) I am speaking on the history of the R statistical software environment as part of a virtual panel for a Lunch &amp;amp; Learn. I like how they used “featuring” in the announcement. It is like I am a hip-hop star! The title of my talk is, A History of R (in 15 minutes…and mostly in pictures).
R @ 25 Lunch &amp;amp; Learn: Understanding the Landscape of the Popular Free/Open Source Statistics Software</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APA Style Table in RMarkdown (HTML Version)</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/apa-style-table-in-rmarkdown-html-version/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/apa-style-table-in-rmarkdown-html-version/</guid>
      <description>I will try to replicate the the following table from the 7th edition of the APA Publication Manual.
 Table 7.6 from the 7th edition of the APA Publication Manual (p. 213).   My Process I begin by creating an RMarkdown document that is rendered to HTML.
--- title: &amp;quot;Untitled&amp;quot; author: &amp;quot;Andrew Zieffler&amp;quot; date: &amp;quot;1/12/2020&amp;quot; output: html_document --- In the RMarkdown body, I will load a few packages and set up a data frame to mimic the content from our goal table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APA Tables using RMarkdown: Part 5</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/apa-tables-using-rmarkdown-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/apa-tables-using-rmarkdown-part-5/</guid>
      <description>This is the fifth part of a short blog series I am writing to re-create some of the sample tables found in the 7th edition APA Publication Manual. In this post I will attempt to show how to create a table to present the results of several fitted models. (This type of table is not among the example tables in the 7th edition APA Publication Manual.) To do so, I will incorporate many ideas that I covered in the first, second, third and fourth of these posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APA Tables using RMarkdown: Part 4</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/apa-tables-using-rmarkdown-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/apa-tables-using-rmarkdown-part-4/</guid>
      <description>This is the fourth part of a short blog series I am writing to re-create some of the sample tables found in the 7th edition APA Publication Manual. In this post I will attempt to mimic Table 7.17 (p. 220). To do so, I will incorporate many ideas that I covered in the first, second, and third of these posts.
 Table 7.17 from the 7th edition of the APA Publication Manual (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APA Tables using RMarkdown: Part 3</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/apa-tables-using-rmarkdown-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/apa-tables-using-rmarkdown-part-3/</guid>
      <description>This is the third part of a short blog series I am writing to re-create some of the sample tables found in the 7th edition APA Publication Manual. In this post I will attempt to mimic Table 7.10 (p. 215). To do so, I will incorporate many ideas that I covered in the first and second of these posts.
 Table 7.10 from the 7th edition of the APA Publication Manual (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APA Tables using RMarkdown: Part 2</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/apa-tables-using-rmarkdown-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/apa-tables-using-rmarkdown-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This is the second part of a short blog series I am writing to re-create some of the sample tables found in the 7th edition APA Publication Manual. In this post I will attempt to re-create Table 7.8 (p. 214). To do so, I will incorporate many ideas that I covered in the first of these posts.
 Table 7.8 from the 7th edition of the APA Publication Manual (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APA Tables Using RMarkdown</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/apa-tables-using-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/apa-tables-using-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>Often it is useful to format table output to make it look good or to adhere a particular style (e.g., APA). There are several packages that help in this endeavor when working in an Rmarkdown document. When I create tables using RMarkdown, the primary packages I use are:
 The kable() function from the knitr package; and Functions from the kableExtra package.  There are many packages for formatting tables, among others, include the flextable package, the gt package, the huxtable package, and the expss package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Television</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/television/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/television/</guid>
      <description>In 2017, my wife and I were fed up with the cost of cable television and were considering “cutting the cord”. In addition to cable, we also had Hulu, Netflix, and Amazon Prime, so our hypothesis was that we probably didn’t need cable. Before making the decision to cut cable, I wanted some data to help ensure that I would not be eliminating many of the TV shows that I watched.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to do about p-values?</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/what-to-do-about-p-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/what-to-do-about-p-values/</guid>
      <description>In March, the ASA published a special issue of The American Statistician (TAS) related to statistical inference in the 21st century. In the initial article, Moving to a World Beyond “p &amp;lt; 0.05”, Wassersein, Schirm, and Lazar (2019) write for the ASA saying,
 “The ASA Statement on P-Values and Statistical Significance stopped just short of recommending that declarations of “statistical significance” be abandoned. We take that step here. We conclude, based on our review of the articles in this special issue and the broader literature, that it is time to stop using the term “statistically significant” entirely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 StatPREP Workshops</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2019-statprep-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2019-statprep-workshops/</guid>
      <description>I just finished helping out with two StatPREP workshops in Columbia, Maryland and Fort Worth, Texas, respectively. StatPREP is an initiative of the Mathematical Association of America (MAA), in conjunction with American Mathematical Association of Two-Year Colleges (AMATYC) and the American Statistical Association (ASA), to introduce data and computing into introductory statistics courses—specifically in community college classrooms.
 Summer 2019 StatPREP participants and workshop leaders at Howard Community College  Each summer, workshops are held in four locations, and each location hosts a workshop for two consecutive years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Higher Education in Minnesota</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/higher-education-in-minnesota/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/higher-education-in-minnesota/</guid>
      <description>I was recently perusing a book from 1960, Minnesota Heritage: A Panoramic Narrative of the Historical Development of the North Star State and came across the following map showing the locations of the colleges and universities in the state at the time.
 Figure 1: Minnesota Colleges and Universities in 1960  
The text referring to the map made an inference about the accessibility to higher education,
 At a glance the map shows, these facilities for higher education are quite uneveny distributed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computing Talk at SSC 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/ssc-computing-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/ssc-computing-talk/</guid>
      <description>I am giving a talk at the 46th Annual Meeting of the Statistical Society of Canada in Montreal on June 05, 2018. The talk is part of an invited session on Teaching Statistics to Graduate Students in the Health and Social Sciences. Information, including the slides, is available below.
Title: Statistical Computing: Non-Ignorable Missingness in the Graduate-Level Social Science Curriculum
Abstract: In 2010, Nolan and Temple Lang pointed out that &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Markdown Theme Gallery</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/r-markdown-theme-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/r-markdown-theme-gallery/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown is a great way to integrate R code into a document. An example of the default theme used in R Markdown HTML documents is shown below.
Pre-Packaged Themes There are several other canned themes you can use rather than the default theme. There are 12 additional themes that you can use without installing any other packages: “cerulean”, “cosmo”, “flatly”, “journal”, “lumen”, “paper”, “readable”, “sandstone”, “simplex”, “spacelab”, “united”, and “yeti”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Weather in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/spring-weather-in-minneapolis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/spring-weather-in-minneapolis/</guid>
      <description>It feels like this spring has been especially terrible weather-wise. We have gotten a lot of snow and it has been cold. To evaluate whether this is the case or whether I have hindsight bias, I pulled some historical weather data for the month of April from Weather Underground.
library(dplyr) library(forcats) library(ggplot2) library(ggridges) library(readr) library(viridis) # Read in data april = read_csv(&amp;quot;~/Documents/github/Public-Stuff/data/april-weather.csv&amp;quot;) # Filter dates april = april %&amp;gt;% filter(date &amp;lt;= 11) I grabbed data back to 2008 (avialable at https://raw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minnesota State High School Boys Hockey Predictions (Post Hoc Analysis)</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2018-03-15-boys-hockey-post-hoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2018-03-15-boys-hockey-post-hoc/</guid>
      <description>In two previous posts, post 1 and post 2, I used Monte Carlo simulation to predict the winner of the 2018 Minnesota State High School Boys Hockey tournament. Now that the tournament is over, I wanted to analyze how the model did and also think about ways to improve the predictions should I want to re-run such a simulation in the future.
Accuracy of the Predictions So, how well did the simulation do in predicting the state tournament champion?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minnesota State High School Boys Hockey Predictions (Updated Quarterfinals)</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2018-03-08-boys-hockey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2018-03-08-boys-hockey/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, I used Monte Carlo simulation to predict the winner of the 2018 Minnesota State High School Boys Hockey tournament. Now that the quarterfinal games have been played, I thought I would update my predictions. The process for this is to:
 Update the Elo ratings based on the quarterfinal games; Re-simulate the tournament  I simulated the Class A state tournament 10,000 times using the same process as described in my previous post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minnesota State High School Boys Hockey Predictions</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2018-03-03-boys-hockey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2018-03-03-boys-hockey/</guid>
      <description>The state high school boys hockey tournament, scheduled for March 7–10, is one of the premiere sporting events in the state of Minnesota. According to Wikipedia, this event has drawn over 100,000 spectators 22 times in its history, eclipsing 135,000 spectoators in 2015. Many national caliber players played high school hockey in Minnesota, several taking part in the state tournament. Names like Neal Broten, Herb Brooks, and T. J. Oshie are alumni of state tournaments past.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
