<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Andrew Zieffler</title>
    <link>/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Andrew Zieffler</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>APA Tables using RMarkdown: Part 3</title>
      <link>/post/apa-tables-using-rmarkdown-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/apa-tables-using-rmarkdown-part-3/</guid>
      <description>This is the third part of a short blog series I am writing to re-create some of the sample tables found in the 7th edition APA Publication Manual. In this post I will attempt to mimic Table 7.10 (p. 215). To do so, I will incorporate many ideas that I covered in the first and second of these posts.
 Table 7.10 from the 7th edition of the APA Publication Manual (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APA Tables using RMarkdown: Part 2</title>
      <link>/post/apa-tables-using-rmarkdown-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/apa-tables-using-rmarkdown-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This is the second part of a short blog series I am writing to re-create some of the sample tables found in the 7th edition APA Publication Manual. In this post I will attempt to re-create Table 7.8 (p. 214). To do so, I will incorporate many ideas that I covered in the first of these posts.
 Table 7.8 from the 7th edition of the APA Publication Manual (p.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APA Tables Using RMarkdown</title>
      <link>/post/apa-tables-using-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/apa-tables-using-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>Often it is useful to format table output to make it look good or to adhere a particular style (e.g., APA). There are several packages that help in this endeavor when working in an Rmarkdown document. When I create tables using RMarkdown, the primary packages I use are:
 The kable() function from the knitr package; and Functions from the kableExtra package.  There are many packages for formatting tables, among others, include the flextable package, the gt package, the huxtable package, and the expss package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thesis Season</title>
      <link>/post/thesis-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/thesis-season/</guid>
      <description>It is the time of the semester when it seems every graduate student wants to make progress on their milestones, and several oral prelim exams and thesis defenses get crammed into a 1–2 week period. In the spirit of what I call “Thesis Season”, here are some good reads to keep this all in perspective.
Luke Burns wrote an inspired piece for McSweeney’s entitled FAQ: The “Snake Fight” Portion of Your Thesis Defense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissertation Writing</title>
      <link>/post/dissertation-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/dissertation-writing/</guid>
      <description>Many times I see students get paralyzed by the idea of writing dissertation (or paper). Anne Lamott gives this advice to struggling writers:
Thirty years ago, my older brother, who was ten years old at the time, was trying to get a report on birds written that he’d had three months to write. [It] was due the next day. We were out at our family cabin in Bolinas, and he was at the kitchen table close to tears, surrounded by binder paper and pencils and unopened books on birds immobilized by the hugeness of the task ahead.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>