<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EPsy-3264 on Andrew Zieffler</title>
    <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/tags/epsy-3264/</link>
    <description>Recent content in EPsy-3264 on Andrew Zieffler</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.datadreaming.org/tags/epsy-3264/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>College in the Schools</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2018-02-19-college-in-the-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/2018-02-19-college-in-the-schools/</guid>
      <description>College in the Schools is a concurrent enrollment program in which existing University of Minnesota courses are taught in high schools by high school teachers. All schools wishing to offer a CIS course go through an application process, including an interview and approval by the post-secondary academic department sponsoring the course of any high school teachers who will be teaching the course.
Since CIS is a concurrent enrollment program, students are enrolled simultaneously in the University of Minnesota course (EPsy 3264: Basic and Applied Statistics) and a course at their high school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EPsy 3264: Basic and Applied Statistics</title>
      <link>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/epsy-3264-basic-and-applied-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.datadreaming.org/post/epsy-3264-basic-and-applied-statistics/</guid>
      <description>EPsy 3264 is a 3-credit course designed to engage students using a modeling and simulation approach to inference. This course fulfills the Mathematical Thinking component of the Liberal Education requirements at the University of Minnesota. Statistics is more than just an application of mathematics or a methodology used in some other discipline. Statistics is a principled way of thinking about the world. In particular, it is a principled approach to data collection, prediction, and scientific inference.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
